<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="ParadiseConstruction">
        <item>Floor</item>
        <item>Light Floor</item>
        <item>Walls</item>
        <item>Reinforced walls</item>
        <item>Grille</item>
        <item>Glass panels</item>
        <item>Reinforced glass panels</item>
        <item>WindowDoor</item>
        <item>Hidden Door</item>
        <item>Table</item>
        <item>APC</item>
        <item>Air Alarm</item>
        <item>Intercom Radio</item>
        <item>Fire Alarm</item>
        <item>Airlock</item>
        <item>Computers</item>
        <item>AI Core</item>
        <item>Machine</item>
        <item>Light Fixture</item>
        <item>Security Camera</item>
        <item>Turrets</item>
        <item>Recharge Station</item>
        <item>Flamethrower</item>
        <item>Disposal Pipes and Machinery</item>
        <item>Solar Panels and Trackers</item>
        <item>Bookcase</item>
        <item>Locker</item>
        <item>Display Case</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="ParadiseConstructionFloor"
        >Place rods on space.
Then place floor tile on top of that.
Then place any type of flooring on top of that for decoration.
Deconstruction
For all floors, use a crowbar on a floor tile to remove it
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionLight_Floor"
        >Assuming there already is a plating
Use the wire on glass
Use the metal on the tile you get
Place the light tile on the plating
Deconstruction
If you\'re working on a light floor, you can further dismantle the light floor tile:
Use a crowbar on the light tile to remove the metal
Use wirecutters on the resulting tile to separate wires from glass
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionWalls"
        >Click the metal in your hand to open the construction panel,
Choose \'Build wall girders\' from the list
Use the remaining 2 sheets of metal on the girders
Deconstruction
Weld off the plating
Wrench the girders apart
Alternately, you can use a Crowbar to dislodge the girders and drag them out of the way
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionReinforced_walls"
        >Click the metal in your hand to open the construction panel,
Choose \'Build wall girders\' form the list
Use the plasteel on the girders to reinforce them
Use the last plasteel sheet on the reinforced girders to finish the wall
Deconstruction
Wirecutters.
Screwdriver.
Welder.
Crowbar.
Wrench.
Welder.
Crowbar.
Screwdriver.
Wirecutters.
Wrench.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionGrille"
        >Stand where you wish the grille to be placed
Click on the stack of 2 rods with the hand you have them in
Deconstruction
Use wirecutters.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionGlass_panels"
        >One directional
Click the glass pane
Click the "one direct" button
Right-click the new pane and rotate it
Use the screwdriver to fasten it down
Alternatively:
Use the glass on a grille.
Right-click the new pane and rotate it
Use the screwdriver to fasten it down
Full
Click the glass pane
Click the "full" button
Use the screwdriver to fasten it down
Deconstruction
Screwdriver to detach it from its sockets
Wrench to deconstruct the glass into a sheet of glass
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionReinforced_glass_panels"
        >One directional
 Click the reinforced glass pane
 Click the "one direct" button
 Right-click the new pane and rotate it
 Screwdriver (Secure frame to floor.)
 Crowbar (Pop pane in.)
 Screwdriver (Secure pane.)

 Alternatively:
 Use the reinforced glass on a grille.
 Right-click the new pane and rotate it
 Screwdriver (Secure frame to floor.)
 Crowbar (Pop pane in.)
 Screwdriver (Secure pane.)

Full

Click the reinforced glass pane
 Click the "full" button
 Screwdriver
 Crowbar
 Screwdriver

Deconstruction

Screwdriver to loosen the pane.
 Crowbar to pop it out.
 Screwdriver to unscrew the frame.
 Wrench to deconstruct the glass.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionWindowDoor"
        >Click the reinforced glass pane
 Click the "Windoor" button
 Wrench
 Plasteel (Optional: To create a secure windoor)
 Cable
 Airlock Electronics
 Crowbar

Deconstruction

 Open the windoor
 Screwdriver
 Crowbar the airlock electronics out
 Wirecutters
 Wrench
 Welder
 (Note: as of right now an emagged windoor can not be deconstructed, harmed, or repaired. It is invincible)
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionHidden_Door"
        >Regular
 Click the metal in your hand to open the construction panel,
 Choose \'Build wall girders\' form the list
 Use crowbar on girders and wait a few seconds for the girders to dislodge.
 Use the remaining 2 sheets of metal on the girders

To turn a wall into a hidden door, follow the deconstruction guide for the wall type until the final wrenching, and instead proceed from the "Use crowbar on girders" line above.

Reinforced
Click the metal in your hand to open the construction panel,
 Choose \'Build wall girders\' form the list
 Use crowbar on girders and wait a few seconds for the girders to dislodge.
 Use the reinforced metal on the dislodged girders twice to finish it

Deconstruction
Hidden Door (Regular or Reinforced)
 Screwdriver
 Welder
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionTable"
        >Use two sheets of metal to construct table parts
 Use the collapsed table on itself while holding it in your hand
Deconstruction
Wrench to disassemble the table.

Reinforced Table
Use four metal rods on some table parts
 Use the collapsed table on itself while holding it in your hand

Deconstruction
 Welder to weaken the table.
 Wrench to disassemble it.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionAPC"
        > Use the metal and make an APC frame
 Use the frame on the wall you want the APC on.
 Fit it with the wire coil.
 Fit it with the Power Control Module.
 Screwdriver the electronics into place.
 Add the Power Cell.
 Crowbar shut. It starts ID locked, with the cover engaged and the main switch turned off.

APCs may only be placed in areas which have been defined as a Station Area using the Chief Engineer\'s Station Blueprints. If you\'re trying to replace a broken APC, you can get the cover off by breaking it, likely with a fire extinguisher, or with a crowbar.
Deconstruction
Requires
Screwdriver, Wirecutters, Crowbar, Welder, Authorized ID

 Swipe Card to unlock APC.
 Remove Power Cell.
 Screwdriver to unsecure electronics.
 Crowbar to lift floor tile in front of APC
 Wirecutters to remove cables.
 Crowbar to remove Power Control Board.
 Welder to remover from wall.
 Wrenching the frame that is now detached from the wall de-constructs it to two metal sheets.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionAir_Alarm"
        >Construction
Requires
2 x Metal, 1x Wire coil, 1x Circuitboard Air Alarm Electronics, Screwdriver

 Use the metal and make an air alarm frame.
 Use the frame on the wall you want it on.
 Put in the electronics.
 Wire it with 5 cable pieces.
 Screwdriver to close.

Deconstruction
Requires
Screwdriver, Wirecutters, Crowbar, Wrench

Open cover with screwdriver.
Cut all the wires using wirecutters.
Cut the remaining wires by clicking on the airalarm with wirecutters.
Pry out the circuit using the crowbar.
Remove the frame from the wall using the wrench.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionIntercom_Radio"
        >Construction
Requires
2 x Metal, 1x Wire coil, 1x Circuitboard Intercom Electronics, Screwdriver

 Use the metal and make an intercom frame.
 Use the frame on the wall you want it on.
 Put in the electronics.
 Wire it with 5 cable pieces.
 Screwdriver to close.

Deconstruction
Requires
Screwdriver, Wirecutters, Crowbar, Welder, (Optional) Welding Helmet

Open cover with screwdriver.
Cut all the wires using wirecutters.
Cut the remaining wires by clicking on the intercom with wirecutters.
Pry out the circuit using the crowbar.
(Optional) To prevent eye damage, put on a welder mask or goggles.
Remove the frame from the wall using the welder.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionFire_Alarm"
        >Construction
Requires
2 x Metal, 1x Wire coil, 1x Circuitboard Fire Alarm Electronics, Screwdriver

 Use the metal and make an air alarm frame.
 Use the frame on the wall you want it on.
 Put in the electronics.
 Wire it with 5 cable pieces.
 Screwdriver to close.

Deconstruction
Requires
Screwdriver, Wirecutters, Crowbar, Wrench

Open cover with screwdriver.
Cut the wires by clicking on the firealarm with wirecutters.
Pry out the circuit using the crowbar.
Remove the frame from the wall using the wrench.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionAirlock"
        >Construction
Requires
4 x Metal, 1x Reinforced glass, 1x Wire coil, Wrench, Screwdriver, 1x Circuitboard

 Use the metal and make an Airlock Assembly
 Wrench it inplace
 Use pen to name the Airlock (OPTIONAL)
 Add reinforced glass (Only if you wish to make a glass airlock)
 Add wires
 Unlock the airlock electronic board with an ID
 Use the airlock electronic board and set the access level
 Add the airlock electronic board to the airlock frame.
 Screwdriver to finish

Deconstruction
Requires
Welder, Wrench, Screwdriver, Wirecutters, Crowbar, Multitool

 Screwdriver the door.
 Use multitool and wirecutters to disable everything except the doorbolts as detailed here. Doorbolts must be up for this to work.
 Weld the door shut.
 Crowbar the electronics out. (if the door is electrified, this won\'t work for some reason)
 Wirecut the wires out.
 Unsecure it with a wrench.
 Weld it to deconstruct to metal plates.

Cannot be done to an emagged airlock. RCD deconstruction must be used for that. It is possible to build a new airlock over the emagged one.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionComputers"
        >Construction
Requires
5 x Metal, 2x Glass, 1x Wire coil (5 pieces), Wrench, Screwdriver, 1x Circuitboard

 Use the metal to open the construction panel
 Choose Computer frame
 Wrench it inplace
 Insert Circuitboard
 Screwdriver
 Wires
 glass
 Screwdriver to finish

Deconstruction
Requires
Welder, Wrench, Screwdriver, Wirecutters, Crowbar

 Screwdriver to detach the screen.
 Crowbar to pry off the screen.
 Wirecutters to cut the cables.
 Screwdriver to detach the circuit lid.
 Crowbar to pry out the circuit.
 Wrench to detach the frame.
 Welder to disassemble the frame.

Returns all components used in construction.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionAI_Core"
        >Construction
Requires
4 x Reinforced metal, 2x Reinforced Glass, 1x Wire Coil, Wrench, Screwdriver, 1x AI Circuitboard, optional: Human brain

 0AICore.pngBuild Frame from 4 reinforced sheets
 Wrench into place
 1AICore.pngAdd AI Core circuit board
 2AICore.pngScrewdriver
 3AICore.pngAdd wires
 4AICore.pngAdd brain placed in an MMI (only if you want a NEW AI)
 5AICore.pngAdd reinforced glass
 Screwdriver

Deconstruction

While you can\'t outright disassemble an AI after it is built there are ways to deal with it.

    Intellicard can be used to transfer the AI\'s consciousness, or kill/wipe it
    Wrench can be used on the core to move it
    The AI Core is vulnerable to attacks, bombs etc
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionMachine"
        >Their construction detailed in the machine construction guide.
So yeah check the wiki. Every machine is different.
Deconstruction
Requires
Screwdriver, Crowbar, Wirecutters, Wrench

 Screwdriver to open the cover.
 Crowbar to pry out the circuit.
 Wirecutters to remove the wires.
 Wrench to disassemble the frame.

Usually returns all or most components used in construction. Some components may become broken.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionLight_Fixture"
        >Construction
Requires
2 x Metal, 1x Wire Coil, light tube/bulb,Screwdriver

 Build frame from 2 metal sheets (or 1 metal sheet for small lights)
 Place frame on wall
 Add wires
 Screwdriver
 Add light tube (or light bulb for small fixtures)
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionSecurity_Camera"
        >Construction
Requires
1 x Camera Assembly, 1x Wire Coil, Wrench, Welder, Screwdriver

 Place the camera assembly on the tile where\'d you like the camera to be.
 Wrench it into position
 Weld it to the wall.
 Add any additional upgrades. Plasma sheet for EMP proof, analyzer for x-ray, and proximity sensor for motion sensing (OPTIONAL)
 Add wire.
 Screwdriver the camera to complete it.
 Set camera network (default is SS13)
 Set camera direction

For upgrades, insert solid plasma for EMP proofing, an analyzer for X-Ray and a proximity sensor for Motion.
Deconstruction
Requires
Screwdriver, Wirecutters, Crowbar, Wrench, Welder

 Screwdriver the camera to open the back panel.
 Use your wirecutter to cut all the wires. (Cutting the alarm wire is optional)
 Use your welder to unweld the camera from the wall.
 Wrench the camera to unattach it from the wall.
 Crowbar the camera assembly to remove any upgrades.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionTurrets"
        >Construction
requires
7 x Metal, Wrench, Screwdriver, Welder, 1 x any energy-based gun , 1 x proximity sensor

 Build a turret frame from metal
 Use a wrench to secure the turret frame(it can be moved around before being secured)
 Use metal on the turret frame to build the cover
 Use a wrench on the frame to bolt the cover
 Add the gun
 Add the prox sensor
 Use a screwdriver to secure it all
 Use more metal on the frame
 Finally use a welder to secure the second layer of metal

 Deconstruction

 Shoot it a bunch of times

</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionRecharge_Station"
        >Recharge Station
Deconstruction
Requires
Screwdriver, Crowbar, Wirecutters, Wrench, Authorized ID

 Unlock the charger with an ID
 Screwdriver to open the cover.
 Wrench to dislodge the internal plating.
 Wirecutters to remove the wires.
 Crowbar to remove the components.

Usually returns all or most components used in construction. Some components may become broken.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionFlamethrower"
        >Requires
1 x Rods, Screwdriver, Welder, Igniter, 1 x plasma tank

 Screwdriver the welder
 Add rods to the welder to create the flamethrower
 Screwdriver the igniter
 Add the igniter to the flamethrower
 Screwdriver to finish
 Load a plasma tank- high pressures work best

You can also get one from a hacked Autolathe, minus the plasma tank. It is not very useful but it is used in science and it can destroy alien weeds.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionDisposal_Pipes_and_Machinery"
        >Construction
Requires
1 x Disposal Pipe/Machine, Welder, Wrench, Crowbar

 Retrieve the pipe/machine from the Disposal Pipe Dispenser (found in Atmosia)
 Crowbar floortile if exists to access plating
 Move pipe over plating, rotate and flip using the rightclick menu
 Wrench pipe
 Weld pipe

Deconstruction
Requires
Screwdriver, Welder, Wrench

 If Disposal Bin, turn off the pump
 Screwdriver to remove power connection
 Welder on machine to remove its joints
 Wrench to detach it from the plating
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionSolar_Panels_and_Trackers"
        >Construction
Requires
Solar Assembly, Wrench, Glass or Reinforced Glass, Tracker Electronics (OPTIONAL)

 Place the solar assembly on where you want to construct your solar panel/tracker. To connect it to a wire you must construct it under a wire node.
 Wrench the solar assembly into place.
 Add the electronics if you want to create a solar tracker (OPTIONAL)
 Finish the construction by placing glass, or reinforced glass, into the assembly frame.

Deconstruction
Requires
Crowbar, Wrench

 Take out the panel with a crowbar.
 If you are deconstructing a tracker, you can take out the electronics with your crowbar (OPTIONAL)
 Unwrench the leftover assembly from it\'s place and you will be able to move it.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionBookcase"
        >Construction
Requires
5 x Planks.png, Wrench,

 Construct a frame with 4 wooden planks.
 Wrench the frame into place.
 Add a plank to the frame to make a shelf.

Deconstruction
Requires
Crowbar, Wrench,

 Crowbar out the shelf.
 Unsecure the frame with a wrench.
 Break apart the frame with a crowbar.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionLocker"
        >Construction

 Open the metal construction menu by using the metal on itself
 Select locker from the construction list

Deconstruction
Requires
Welder

 Open the locker.
 Weld the locker.
</string>
    <string name="ParadiseConstructionDisplay_Case"
        >Construction
Requires
5 x Metal, 5x Glass, Screwdriver, 1x Circuitboard, optional: Proximity Sensor

 Use the metal and make a machine frame.
 Add the glass to the machine frame.
 Unlock the airlock electronic board with an ID.
 Use the airlock electronic board and set the access level.
 Add the airlock electronic board to the machine frame.
 Optional: Add a proximity sensor to enable the burglar alarm.
 Screwdriver to finish.

Deconstruction
Requires
Wrench, Crowbar

 Unlock the display case with an ID card.
 Use the crowbar to pry the frame apart.
 Use the crowbar to remove the airlock electronics.
 Use the crowbar to pry the glass out of the frame.
 Use the wrench to deconstruct the frame.
</string>

</resources>